这样  可以了吗
Are we, uh, almost done here?
我得给我妈打电话
I have to call my mother,
接我女儿  通知医院
get my daughter, call the hospital.
那么他没有威胁你是吗
So he didn't threaten you?
没有
No.
-也没有动手吗  -不算是吧
- No fight? - Not really.
听着像是有
Sounds like a yes.
有没有任何迹象表明会发生这样的事呢
Was there any indication that something would happen?
有
Yeah...
我和他度过的每一分钟都是预示
Every moment I spent with him.
他总是伺机要惹出些什么事
He's always waiting for something to happen.
但这次
But this...
知道他会在哪吗
And no idea where he is?
不知道
No.
出现这种矛盾
These domestic situations,
你想息事宁人也挺正常的
it's not uncommon to get cold feet.
你是让我提起诉讼吗
Are you asking me to file charges?
那赶紧给我那些文件
Just give me the paperwork.
如果格利高里·豪斯敢再踏入我的医院
If Greg House steps foot in my hospital again,
或是在其它任何地方接近我
comes anywhere near me.
我就让他进监狱
I want him thrown in jail.
后期:
A.PN
总监：
zlean  sephiroth_8
那么
So...
我们想用什么都可以吗
we can use any of these?
可以
Yeah.
然后对她干什么都行吗
And just do whatever we want to her?
那就是它们的用处
That's what they're there for.
哎  我们正看到精彩处
Hey. We were just getting to the good part.
有精彩的部分吗  这只是表演艺术
Is there a good part? It was performance art.
那是阿夫松·哈米德  她是个天才
That's Afsoun Hamidi. She's a genius.
前不久刚得了麦克阿瑟奖
She just won the MacArthur,
合法证明了这点
legally proving it.
还在泰特现代美术馆办了特展
Just had a retrospective at the Tate Modern.
-没人读《纽约客》吗  -没有
- Nobody reads The New Yorker? - Nope.
但我订阅了她的患者档案
But I subscribe to her patient file.
豪斯  你该休息
House, you should relax.
你今早才手术完
You had surgery this morning.
小手术而已  移动一条引流管
Minor surgery, removing a drain.
是大手术时安装的
Put there during major surgery.
我医生说只要我不离开病床
My doctor says it's okay
就没关系
as long as I don't leave my hospital bed.
哪个说的  苏斯博士还是J博士
Which doctor was that-- Seuss or J?
护士
Nurse.
豪拉尼医生在病历里写了
Dr. Hourani wrote it in his chart.
我很惊讶他竟然同意了
I'm surprised he approved it.
我更惊讶的是你竟然还问了一下
I'm more surprised you actually asked.
我现在做事就是这样有礼貌
I do things like that now.
我要做出一些改变
I'm making some changes...
比如跳到第三十七分钟
like skipping ahead to minute 37.
那是什么  涂料稀释剂吗
What is that-- paint thinner?
我可不想看一个女人被点燃
I'm not gonna watch a woman get set on fire.
没教养的
Philistine.
那个拿着笔记本
Who's the guy with the notebook
内心很纠结的人是谁
who can't decide what to do?
她的助手
Her assistant.
她命令他不得干预
He's been instructed not to intervene.
剧透提示  他还是干预了
Spoiler alert-- he does.
对她来说  还真是"心碎一地"
For her, it is literally heartbreaking.
游戏开始
Let the games begin.
心律失常  红细胞比容升高
Arrhythmia, high hematocrit,
还有非一致性的变异率
and inconsistent RR variability.
你遗漏了第四个症状
You forgot about the fourth symptom--
她就是个疯子
being completely crazy.
别人笑我太疯癫  我笑他人看不穿
One man's crazy is another woman's art.
她的作品探索了很多内容
Her work explores things
比如性别歧视政策和自我形象
like gender politics and self-image.
还有展示带着猴脸面具
And the pressing issue of shaving your entire body
剃光整个身体
in public while wearing a monkey mask.
她目睹自己的母亲自杀
She saw her mom commit suicide
遭继父虐待多年
and was abused by her stepdad for years.
看来疯狂是事出有因
Didn't say the crazy wasn't motivated.
她把那些痛苦转化为艺术
Well, she took that pain and transformed it into art.
这比转化成其它形式好多了
That's better than a lot of the alternatives.
我还是认为她就是疯了
I still vote for nuts.
我们应该用静息态功能磁共振
We should run a resting-state functional MRI
检测背侧接合膜是否更加活跃
to look for increased activity in the dorsal nexus.
她没疯
She's not nuts.
这个带猴脸面具还剃头的人
The monkey-mask-shaving medium
真的很对你的胃口吗
really speaks to you?
让我感兴趣的是她把一堆垃圾
What speaks to me is she's elevated
转变为真正的艺术形式
being full of crap to a genuine art form
而且还大赚一笔
and made a fortune doing it.
人们会花两万元来买她的影碟
People that pay 20 grand for one of her video stills.
另一方面  我们确实需要检察她的背侧接合膜
On the other hand, really do need their dorsal nexi checked.
可能是涂料稀释剂引起的过敏反应
Maybe the paint thinner set off an allergic reaction.
但是没有支气管痉挛
Not without bronchospasm.
在画廊里她旁边有个加热器
There was a space heater next to her in the gallery.
一氧化碳中毒
Carbon monoxide poisoning.
推断符合
It fits.
带她去高压氧舱
Put her in a hyperbaric chamber.
丽莎
Lisa.
你是丽莎·卡迪吧
You're Lisa Cuddy.
有事吗
What's this about?
抱歉打扰了  我是杰瑞·巴雷特
I'm sorry. I'm Jerry Barrett.
我看过你的照片
I recognize you from the photos.
照片根本没能展现出你的魅力
They barely do you justice.
老样子
The usual.
我是你姐姐的朋友
I'm friends with your sister.
她给我看过你照片
She showed me your photos.
我  在对街的银行工作
I-I work at the bank across the street.
茱莉娅是我的客户  她
Um, Julia's my client. She...
想要撮合我们两个
wanted to set us up.
我  恐怕是你认错人了
Oh, I-I'm afraid you have me mixed up with somebody else.
不  我没认错
N-no, I don't think so.
我  你的照片我看过好多次了
I-I've seen many pictures of you several times.
其实我并不是那意思
That didn't sound the way I wanted--
我想大概是因为我长了张大众脸吧
I guess I just have one of those faces.
很高兴认识你
It's nice to meet you.
我也是  在你俩共用的办公室里
Yeah, s-say hi to Lisa Cuddy
遇到丽莎·卡迪时  代我向她问好
when you meet her in the office you share.
真是谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
重症监护病房没有受到
The I.C.U. isn't being attacked by
巨型辐射蜘蛛的袭击
giant radioactive spiders.
我那么发给你的吗
Did I text you that?
那是我的梦境笔记
That was meant for my dream journal.
我想把你的东西还给你
I wanted to return your stuff.
不要担心  我没有离开病房
Don't worry. I didn't go AWOL.
我让我的妻子兼女佣送过来的
I had my wife-maid bring it over.
我的毛衣
My sweater,
一个咖啡杯
a coffee mug,
用过还剩半瓶的乳液
a half-used bottle of lotion,
电影《马利和我》的DVD
and a DVD of Marley & Me.
考虑到你对欧文·威尔逊的那点幻想
Given your thing for Owen Wilson,
我以为你会希望尽快拿到最后的两样东西
I thought you might want those last two back asap.
没听明白
I don't get it.
你以欧文·威尔逊为幻想对象自慰过
You masturbate to Owen Wilson.
我是指盒子
I meant the box.
是种象征性的姿态而已
It's a symbolic gesture.
我希望一切能恢复到
I want things to go back to the way they were
我们未谈恋爱时的样子
before we started dating--
不再恶语相向
no more bad feelings,
不再藕断丝连  只谈工作
no more issues, just work.
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming.
你自残后  我还没和你谈过
I haven't even spoken to you since you hurt yourself.
我是有点自我毁灭
I was self-destructive.
不会有下一次了
It won't happen again.
我要洗心革面
I'm making changes.
不会再做蠢事了
I'm gonna stop doing stupid things.
很好
Great.
谈谈你为什么那么做  会是个明智的决定
The smart thing to do would be to talk about why you did it.
如果你不明白
If you don't understand--
我想不用谈论我老妈  我也不会
I think I could avoid putting another hole in my leg
再往腿上捅个窟窿了
without talking about my mother.
我可不想再接到
Well, I don't want to find out you're wrong
你躺在血淋淋的浴缸里打来的电话
by getting another phone call from you in a bloody bathtub.
我深信  让过去成为过去
I'm a big believer that the best way
的最好方法
to get past the past is to shoot it in the head,
就是把它深埋心底  绝口不提
bury it in a deep pit, and pour lye on it.
我只是想请你谈谈这事
I'm just asking you to talk about it.
这是你欠我的
You owe me.
不说我救了你性命
Forget about saving your life.
单单你让我女儿深受那可恶的
You exposed my daughter to
海盗卡通的荼毒  你也该和我谈谈
that obnoxious pirate cartoon.
明天给我送午饭
Bring me lunch tomorrow,
我们再探讨我的内心世界
and we can plumb my depths.
我早该知道画廊的通风条件不好
I should have known the gallery wasn't ventilated enough.
如果不是你阻止了那个人
Hey, if it wasn't for you, we'd be treating her
我们可能同时要治疗她的三度烧伤了
for third-degree burns, too.
那是个错误
That was a mistake.
他不该干涉的
He shouldn't have interfered.
我说了  我很抱歉
I told you I'm sorry.
我想像你那样专注于此具有献身精神
I want to share your commitment,
但有时候对我来说太难了
but it's hard for me sometimes.
譬如她在创新博物馆
Like when she read your love letters
大庭广众下读你的情书那会
in the middle of the New Museum?
对头  我也读《纽约客》
Yes, I read The New Yorker.
那是一年前的事了
That was a year ago.
我们  现在已经分手了
And we're-- we're not together anymore.
说真的  你不是
Seriously, you weren't
真打算让那人在你身上放火吧
really gonna let that guy set you on fire.
他不过是吸引观众的托  对吧
He was just a plant to get the crowd going, right?
如果那是你的理解  我也无所谓
If that's your interpretation, I welcome it.
阿夫松认为向他人解释她的工作
Afsoun believes explaining her work
会限制工作的潜能
limits its potential.
但在常人看来  他就是个彻头彻尾的混蛋
But between us, he was real and a total dick.
没有哪个疯子会为了艺术
No sane person would let themselves
而甘愿被活活烧死
be burned alive for the sake of art.
我的工作  就是要强制观众
My work is meant to force the audience
打破常规  以新的视角看事情
to break with the rational and see things in a new way.
这样啊  那也没有哪个疯子
Fine. No sane person
会甘愿让自己被活活烧死
would let themselves be burned alive
只为"打破常规"
to "Break with the rational."
我想
I feel...
卢卡  把你身后的氧气面罩递给我
Luca, hand me the oxygen mask behind you.
卢卡
Luca!
恭喜
Congratulations.
不过还只是个妊娠囊
It's a gestational sac.
现在太早  看不到什么
Can't see anything this early.
我知道
I know.
我只是觉得这样能帮我
I just figured this would help me process
理出头绪
what's happening.
太多事情需要考虑
There's a lot we got to figure out.
有将近八个月的时间去想呢
We have almost eight months.
你不会改变想法了吧
You're not having doubts, are you?
没有
No.
你呢
Are you?
绝对没有
Definitely not.
这就是小鲁本的暖巢了
Nice, cozy home for little Ruben.
这是姓氏
It's a family name.
这是一种三明治
It's a sandwich.
以我的家族命名的三明治
Named for my family.
豪斯打来的
It's just House.
我对天起誓  你敢再干涉我的生活试试
I swear to God, stay out of my personal life.
这有什么不好的
Where is the downside here?
杰瑞多可爱
Huh? Jerry is cute.
他是位高级副总裁
He's a senior V.P.
他每年冬天都去哥斯达黎加玩风筝冲浪
He kite-surfs in Costa Rica every winter,
而且他爱他妈妈
and he loves his mother.
只有冬日才爱母吗
Seasonally?
还是说冬日才冲浪
Or is that just the kite-surfing?
是因为豪斯吗
Is this about House?
你在说什么
What?
你觉得我暗地里祈祷自己能够拥有
Like I secretly wish I could alter
改变世界的力量  来改变我们的性格
the laws of the universe, change who we are,
然后就能奇迹般的在一起了吗
and magically make it work out?
一点没错  我就想问这个
Yes, that's exactly what I'm asking.
我刚才的讽刺口吻告诉你  你错了
My sarcasm indicated no.
不  你的讽刺口吻告诉我
No, your sarcasm indicated
你压根不想谈这件事
you wanted to avoid actually saying anything.
听着  丽莎
Look, Lisa...
我只看到你进退两难
All I know is you seem stuck.
而我不想放任你自生自灭
And I don't like seeing you like that.
接受高压氧治疗后  她的病情反而加重了
She got worse in the hyperbaric chamber.
不是一氧化碳中毒
It's not C.O. poisoning.
可能是感染
I think we should consider infection
我们应该检查一下她的助手
and test the assistant.
我无法唤起他的注意  他两眼发直
I couldn't get his attention. He was in a daze.
你认为那是个症状吗  他爱上她了
You think that's a symptom?  He's in love with her.
或许已迷失心智  不知该怎么做好
He was probably overwhelmed, couldn't decide what to do.
她住院后他都做了什么
What's he been doing since she was admitted?
他有没有
Did he bring anything
从病房带什么到治疗室
from the patient room to the treatment room?
带了一些  一个手袋
A few things-- a handbag,
鲜花  毛绒大象
flowers, stuffed elephant.
她看上去像那种
Does she seem like the kind of woman
需要毛绒玩具的女人吗
who needs a stuffed animal?
你打给谁呢
Who are you calling?
当我没问
Oh, of course.
你穿的什么
What are you wearing?
原来我能看见你穿了什么
Oh, I can see what you're wearing.
去她的病房
Go to her room.
现在去检查下那只毛绒大象
Now go address the elephant in the room.
是个专门隐藏摄像头的玩具
This is a nanny cam.
卢卡之所以在治疗室里
The reason Luca couldn't decide
不知该怎么办
what to do in the treatment room
和在画廊时的原因是一样的
is the same as in the gallery.
因为他被告知不准介入
He's been told not to intervene.
真走运
Congratulations.
我们成了她最新的艺术作品
We've become her latest work of art.
我们应该想到的
It shouldn't have surprised us.
她所有的表演都是基于个人的创伤经历
All her work is based on personal traumas.
她让卢卡做记录  拍摄她的治疗过程
She's had Luca taking notes, videotape her treatments,
收集物品  比如尖锐器具和绷带
collect things, like sharps and bandages.
这些全被用来布置画廊
It'll all go into a gallery installation.
我感觉只要是
Well, then I guess as long as
用于正当目的  就没什么问题
the exploitation is properly motivated, it's all okay.
超声显示在她的胰腺处有个囊肿
Ultrasound showed a cyst
我们做了穿刺引流
on her pancreas-- we drained it.
我们干嘛还要讨论这个病例
Why are we even discussing this case?
她骗了我们
She lied to us.
我们可能因此卷入医疗过失纠纷
It's opening us up to malpractice.
只有我们的医疗行为才会让我们陷入医疗过失纠纷
Our practice opens us up to malpractice.
我们要怎么知道她是否真的病了
How do we know she's actually sick?
线索之一就是  她病了
Her being sick is a clue.
为了工作  她愿意让那人
She would have let that guy
以艺术的名义在她身上放火
set her on fire for the sake of her work.
你觉得她还会怕小小的心律失常吗
You think she's scared of a little arrhythmia?
或许她是吸入了油漆稀释剂
She probably huffed paint thinner.
她会让他在她身上放火
She would have let him set her on fire
就是为了保持作品的真实性
because of the honesty of her work.
-装病不符合这条原则  -十三是对的
- Faking an illness doesn't fit. - Thirteen's right.
至少她的结论是对的
At least her conclusion was.
其它部分就错得太可笑了
Everything else was laughably wrong.
如果病人自己诱发了胰腺炎和心脏病
If the patient induced pancreatitis and a heart attack,
那她就是在自杀
she'd be suicidal.
一点没错  她一直都在拿性命冒险
Exactly. She's risking her life all the time.
一点没错  如果她想死
Exactly. If she wanted to be dead,
那她早就死了
she'd be dead a long time ago.
假装死里逃生比被抹水彩更卖座
Pretending to cheat death pays better than water colors.
符合科萨奇B组病毒的症状
Coxsackie B fits.
给她的胆道系统做个螺旋CT
But do a spiral C.T. of her biliary tree
来排除胆结石
to rule out gallstones.
好  我去做CT
Fine. I'll get the C.T.
好  我很高兴和你同去
Sure. I'd be happy to come with you.
谢谢邀请我
Thanks for asking.
你应该躺在床上
You're supposed to stay in bed--
这是医生的嘱咐
doctor's orders.
如果你真的关心我
If you really cared about me,
你打着推翻我理论的小算盘时
you wouldn't be so obvious
就应该含蓄点
when you scheme to prove me wrong.
你主动请缨是因为你想做CT扫描她的肺
You volunteered because you want to C.T. her lungs,
而不是她的胆道系统
not her biliary tree.
你想发现纤维化
You want to find fibrosis
来证明你的"吸入油漆稀释剂"理论
and prove your "Paint thinner" theory.
如果我不跟着你  一旦你失败了
If I don't come with, when you fail,
你就会假装你没做过
you'll pretend you never tried.
我必须得去  是吧
I don't really have a choice, now, do I?
我已经看过你的工资单了
Since I've seen your paycheck,
也许这不太应该
I probably shouldn't.
罐头豆子也没那么差
Canned beans aren't so bad...
在桥下的火堆上煮着
as long as they're cooked over an oil-drum fire
和丐帮帮主一起吃还是不错的
under a bridge with the king of the hobos.
我头晕
I feel dizzy.
皮肤苍白  湿冷
Pale, diaphoretic,
心动过速
tachycardic,
血压80/40
B.P., 80 over 40.
内出血吗
Internal bleeding?
马上把她拉出去做内窥镜
Get her out of here and scope her.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
结肠镜没有发现出血点
The colonoscopy didn't find the bleed,
所以我们只能从肝脏这方面来找找了
so we got to look by your liver.
拜托了  卢卡
Luca, please.
我们必须把一切都记录下来
We need to document everything.
拿一下
Hold this.
我正看到腹主动脉的下面
I'm just below the celiac artery.
没有血
No blood.
有没有可能漏进她的大腿里去了呢
Could it be leaking into her thighs?
没有肿胀和外形改变
No swelling, no asymmetry.
那血去哪里了呢
So where's the blood going?
你检查那里干什么
Why are you looking down there?
因为我不喜欢吃豆子
Cause I don't like beans.
-你放我鸽子  -抱歉
- You stood me up. - Sorry.
应该安排我的病人
Should have scheduled my patient's
周四再内出血
internal bleeding for Thursday.
你又在玩小肚鸡肠
You're still playing the same petty,
消极反抗的游戏了
passive-aggressive games.
真对不起让您大老远跑到
Got you to go all the way to the second floor
您工作的大楼的二层了
of a building you work in.
天啊  我真是狠狠地耍了你啊
Boy, did I screw with you.
是你说你要改变的
You said you were going to change.
看看那个标志
Check the sign.
它说你需要对我特别护理
It says you got to treat me with intensive care.
我在表达我的愤怒  你也该试试
I'm expressing my anger. You should try it.
此时此地  我们好好吵一架吧
Right now, let's finally have our fight.
我们一直都在吵
All we do is fight.
不  你一直都只会恶作剧
No, all you've done is pull pranks
或者冲威尔森发脾气  从不冲我
or have temper tantrums with Wilson, never me,
娶了一个来路不明的妓女
marry mail-order prostitutes,
还强迫我去参加你的婚礼
make me go to your wedding...
多米尼卡是位有执照的美容师
Dominika is a licensed aesthetician.
你切开了自己的腿
You cut open your own leg.
所以你想说这些都是因为你吗
So all this was about you?
你觉得这之间没有关系吗
You don't think it was even related?
豪斯  我们甚至都没
House, we've never even
谈论过我们的分手问题
had a conversation about our breakup.
你显然还对我很生气
You are obviously still angry at me.
而这让我俩都倍受煎熬
And it's hurting both of us.
没想到
Wow, I hadn't realized
午餐有这么大的疗伤效力啊
the incredible healing power of lunch.
我知道一次谈话不能解决所有问题
I know one conversation isn't gonna solve everything,
但它是个开端
but it is a start.
这帘子是用来保护隐私的
It's a privacy curtain.
没有用
It wasn't working.
明天一点  在餐厅吃午餐
Lunch at 1:00, tomorrow in the cafeteria.
这下满意了吧
You happy?
你今天吃了多少片了啊
How many of those have you had today?
不知道  "尼玛"算个数字吗
I don't know. Is "Your mother" a number?
那病人是个骗子
The patient is a fraud.
我在她左侧的足背静脉上发现了注射针孔
I found a puncture in the dorsal vein of her left foot.
注射海洛因无法解释
Shooting up heroin wouldn't explain--
不是海洛因
Not heroin.
她在给自己注射自己的血红细胞
She was injecting herself with her own red blood cells.
这造成了她的心脏问题
It caused her heart issues,
当她红细胞压积持平时
and when her hematocrit evened out,
我们将其误诊为内出血
we mistook it for internal bleeding.
你能得出这么多结论
It must have been a very distinctively shaped
那针孔肯定形状独特且异常健谈
and awfully talkative puncture for you to get all of that.
她电脑上的浏览器历史记录帮了大忙
Browser history on her laptop helped.
她专门研究了血液回输技术
She was researching blood doping
还有其它一些事情
among other things.
-她在研究我  -好几个月了
- She was researching me? - For months.
这与创造瞬时艺术无关
This isn't about creating art in the moment.
都是为了你
It's about you.
她给你设了个套
She set you up.
我们派了一支队伍去他家和医院
We sent a uni over to his apartment and the hospital.
他不会在那里的
Yeah, he won't be there.
那会在哪
Any ideas?
你要是找到他会逮捕他吗
When you find him, you're gonna arrest him?
有任何你觉得我不该那么做的理由吗
Is there some reason you think I shouldn't?
依我的了解  他会去酒吧
Knowing him, he'll be in a bar.
他会找到一家契合他内心感受的酒吧
He'll find one that matches how he feels inside.
那会是你在新泽西能找到
It'll be the most dark,
最阴暗抑郁的角落
depressing hole you can find in New Jersey.
你这次真把我惹毛了
Now you're just pissing me off.
我很抱歉  我不知道她在调查你
I'm really sorry. I-I didn't know she researched you.
我真的不知道...
I had no idea she--
如果你对此一无所知你还插什么话
If you don't know anything, then why are you talking?
请不要怪罪卢卡
Please don't take it out on Luca.
怎么做最能惹毛你我就怎么做
I'll take it out on whoever I think will irritate you the most.
我以为你能理解我这种通过工作
I thought you would understand someone who uses their work
应对疼痛的人
to deal with pain.
我还真不知道搜索引擎
I didn't realize that search engines
可以看透人的灵魂
could look within the soul.
你正穿着病号服站在我面前
You're standing in front of me in a hospital gown.
那又怎样
What the hell was the point of this?
你究竟是想利用哪种创伤
What personal trauma are you exploiting--
不好意思  应该是挖掘其艺术潜质
Sorry--mining for its artistic potential?
我自己的病
My illness.
我是用血液回输骗了你
I did the blood doping to intrigue you,
但我本来已经病了
but I was already ill.
等等  你真的病了吗
Wait. You're really sick?
为什么选我
Why me?
-你知道自己得了什么病吗  -知道
- Do you know what you have? - Yes.
那告诉他
So tell him.
如果我这么做了  对他就没有谜题可言
If I do, there won't be any game for him,
对我们也没有任何艺术可言了
and then there won't be any art for us.
为什么是我
Why me?
我不会回答那些问题的
I don't answer those questions.
你知道我有的是谜题可解
You know, there's a lot of games
而不用对付你这种
I could play that don't involve dealing
自恋装模作样的操纵狂
with narcissistic, manipulative poseurs.
但这是为你量身定做的谜题
But this is a puzzle tailor-made for you.
你不知道我哪些症状是真的
You don't know which of my symptoms are real,
哪些是假的
which are fake,
哪些是我根本没告诉你的
which ones I'm not even telling you about.
我知道这能激起你的好奇心
I know that intrigues you.
你真的打算现在就结束吗
Do you really want to end it now?
不
No.
你想让她浪费我们一个床位吗
You want us to waste a bed on her?
你发过誓
You took an oath...
发誓要很酷
an oath to be cool.
至少当时在别人念那老一套誓词的时候
At least that was the one I mumbled under my breath
我是小声这么说的
while everyone else was doing the boring one.
就算她真的病了  反正我是不相信
Even if she is sick, which I don't believe,
她还说她知道诊断结果
she also says she has a diagnosis.
所以这要么是个谎言要么是个游戏
So it's either just a lie, or it's just a game.
那又怎样
So what?
我喜欢游戏  很有趣  去做血液培养
I like the game. It's fun. Go get a blood culture.
检查寄生虫和细菌
Check for parasites and bacteria.
这就是新生的豪斯吗
This is the new House--
只剩半条腿却双倍的不负责任
half the leg power, twice the irresponsibility?
新生的豪斯是说要让我的生活更加健康
The new House is about making my life healthier.
和你们无关
Never said anything about yours.
去抽血吧
Go get her blood.
我去
I'll do it.
他最近过得很不好
He's going through a tough patch right now.
如果这能转移他的注意力
If this is the distraction he needs
让他老实呆在病床上的话
to keep him in his hospital bed,
我肯定这比其它任何选择都好
I'm sure it's better than any of the alternatives.
这话真是太屈尊俯就了
That was incredibly condescending.
有用吗
Did it work?
你为什么一直拒接你老婆的电话
Why do you keep ducking your wife's calls?
前妻
Ex-wife.
我肯定她只是想祝贺你
I'm sure she just wants to congratulate you
搞大了二十二岁女护士的肚子
about knocking up a 22-year-old nurse.
我还没跟她说
I haven't told her yet.
但是你跟她说过
But you have told her
你不会再跟她同归于床了  是吧
you're not gonna sleep with her anymore, right?
你准备咋知会她啊
How are you planning on letting her know?
直接请她来参加你儿子的割礼吗
Just invite her to the bris?
我正研究怎么说能让她少受点打击
I'm trying to let her down easy.
瑞秋一直都不想要小孩
Rachel never wanted to have kids.
我不想伤害她的感情
I don't want to hurt her feelings.
是啊  你好重感情啊
Yeah. You are all about feelings.
我爱瑞秋爱了二十年
I've loved Rachel for 20 years.
要是她因为这事再也不理我了怎么办
What if she never speaks to me again?
她早晚都会知道
She's gonna find out.
最好是你告诉她的
It better be from you.
这事儿你真蒙不过去
You can't cheat your way out of this one.
怎么了
What is it?
就是有点恶心
Oh, just the nausea.
之前她说她后背疼来着
She said her back was hurting earlier.
要是痛感分十度  你背疼达到多少
What's the pain level on a scale of one to ten?
五度
Five.
怎么确定她说的是实话
How do we know we can take her word for it?
不能  好玩吧
We can't. Fun, huh?
转过身
Roll on your side.
Grey Turner症[胰腺炎典型体征]
Grey Turner's sign.
游戏玩够了
We're done playing.
你的胰腺正在释放消化酶
Your pancreas is releasing corrosive enzymes.
它会把周围的脏器都消化光
It'll eat away at the surrounding organs.
这点你肯定知道
But you must know that.
给你做诊断的大夫应该跟你说过
The doctor who diagnosed you would have said
不做治疗会出现什么后果
what will happen if you don't get treatment.
告诉他们吧
Just tell them.
如果你知道自己到底怎么了
If you know what's wrong with you,
告诉他们好让他们治好你
tell them so they can fix it.
我们一起合作过多少作品了
How many projects have we done together?
你总是那么担心
You're always so worried.
有哪次你相信了我而出错的吗
Have you ever gone wrong trusting me?
咱们引流过的那个胰腺囊肿
That pancreatic cyst we drained--
它又长回来了  而且病人毫不在意
it's back, and she doesn't care at all.
你觉得她就是想寻死
You think she actually is suicidal.
我是这么想
I would,
但她是怎么让自己长出囊肿的
but how did she give herself the cysts?
毒物筛检是阴性的
Tox screen was negative,
而且也没有外伤迹象
and there's no sign of trauma.
还有一种解释
There is another explanation.
她对此毫无反应
The reason she didn't react
不是因为她一心想死
isn't 'cause she wants to die.
而是因为她无计可施
It's 'cause she knows she can't do anything about it.
不管她得的是什么  都是致命的
Whatever she has is fatal.
这应该能缩小范围了
That should narrow it down.
我们在这里干什么
What are we doing here?
验证一个理论
Testing a theory.
基于一些你不懂的东西
It's based on some stuff you can't understand,
比如说变异率
like RR variability,
还有些你能懂的
and some stuff you can,
比如四个月前她的一场行为艺术
like the fact that she shaved her head
给自己削了发
in an art piece four months ago.
那是一种诠释社会的...
That was a commentary on society's--
那是一种诠释
It was a commentary on the fact
她的头发不剃也得全掉光
that it was gonna fall out anyway,
而她这么做是想掩盖其原因
and she wanted to hide why.
癌症吗
Cancer?
你  你确定吗
Are--are you sure about that?
看到她的脑仁旁边那个
See that tumor-ish thingamajig
像肿瘤一样的玩意了吗
near her "Brainamabob"?
哦  上帝
Oh, God.
你的明白
Are you getting this?
游戏结束  本人胜出
Game's over. I won.
原发性中枢神经系统淋巴瘤
Primary CNS lymphoma
伴相关副肿瘤综合征
with associated paraneoplastic syndrome.
真的是这样吗
Is that really what it is?
是
Yes.
四个月之前
Four months ago,
我出现了视觉和平衡障碍
I had some vision and balance problems,
在纽约仁爱医院确诊
and New York Mercy diagnosed me.
肿瘤太靠近脑干无法切除
The tumor was too close to the brain stem to cut out,
所以他们给我做了几个疗程的放疗
so they did a few rounds of radiation.
但是没有效果  就让我出院了
But it didn't work, and they sent me home.
你就是那段时间跟我分手的
That was around the time you broke up with me.
我们在图一时的欢愉
We were having a fling.
把你卷进来对你不公平
It wouldn't have been fair to involve you.
我现在卷进来了
I'm involved now.
你就是不愿对我敞开心扉
You just didn't want to open up.
卢卡  我当时意识不清晰
Luca, my mind was not clear then.
然后你觉醒了
And then you cleared it.
你觉得可以利用你的行将死去
Then you realized you could use your death
来完成一个巨作
to make your magnum opus.
也许你是想证明没人能逃过一死
Maybe you wanted to show that no one can cheat death,
即使一群拥有无限资源的医生也束手无策
even an entire team of doctors with unlimited resources.
或者是最初确诊你的医生
Or maybe your first doctors
没把你当人看  而是看成了一堆病症
didn't treat you like a person-- just a series of symptoms.
你想要重现这种非人性行为
You wanted to re-create that depersonalization.
而我是你的实验对象
And I was the man to see.
如果我以前那么想过
If that was what I thought,
在也不再这样认为了
I don't any longer.
你花时间和我在一起
You spent time with me.
带入了个人情感
You took this personally.
不  我没有
No, I didn't.
而且我一点不觉得你的作品有什么意义
And I don't actually think your piece is about anything.
我觉得  你不过是发现人生难逃一死
I think you just figured out that you're mortal.
自己不过是一堆细胞与代谢废物
You're just a bag of cells and waste
最终将化为坟中的一掊土
with an expiration date.
你要出格的表演  想引起人们注意
You wanted to act out. You wanted people to notice.
可能你还祈祷这次的结果会不一样
Maybe you even prayed for a different answer this time.
我给你的作品起了个名字
I got a title for your piece--
味同嚼蜡
"It Doesn't Mean Anything".
你又伪造我的签名开处方了
You're forging my name on prescriptions again.
错
No.
你说的好像我有哪次不是这么干似的
What you just said implies that I stopped at some point.
二十分钟前  我通知了所有本地药房
20 minutes ago, I put a notice out to all local pharmacies
在给我的处方开药前
to require verbal authorization
都需要我的口头授权
before filling my prescriptions.
你这就是给自己找麻烦
You have any idea how much extra work you've just given yourself?
连一周你都坚持不了
You're not gonna last a week.
你的这种行为我容忍了很多年
I've been dealing with this for years.
但现在我不干了
But it's over--
这有害于你的肝脏  听力
your liver, your hearing,
更别说你冒名签的每个处方
never mind the fact that each scrip you write
都是一项重罪
is a separate felony.
你会坐牢的  我也会被牵连
You will serve time, so could I.
你选择在这个时候
You've chosen this moment
来埋怨我嗑维可丁吗
to give me crap about my Vicodin use?
你三天前才开的药
You filled this three days ago.
现在一半都没了
Now it's almost half gone.
我的腿不也是这样
So is my leg.
这是一个月的用量
It's a month supply.
你现在服用的剂量
The amount you're taking has nothing to do
-对缓解躯体疼痛没有作用  -好吧
- with physical pain.  - Okay.
也许我是想让自己麻木一点
So maybe I am trying to numb myself a little,
因为我在尝试改变
because I'm trying to change,
尝试不要自我毁灭
trying to stop being self-destructive.
你就一定要用自残的方式
So you can only handle not self-destructing
来缓解你的自我毁灭倾向吗
by being self-destructive?
你想让我怎么样
What do you want from me?
我不知道  豪斯  但我担心你
I don't know, House, but I'm worried about you.
我不想再这样
I don't know how many times I can watch you
看着你自我摧残
cut off pieces of yourself.
这次是重症监护病房  下次可能是停尸房
Now it's the I.C.U. Next time it'll be the morgue.
你感到痛苦
You're miserable.
也很愤怒
And you're angry.
而我希望你能直面这些问题
And I want you to actually deal with that
而不是通过嗑药来逃避
and not just try to medicate the issue away.
不
No.
你知道我现在的感觉吗
You know what I feel right now?
我不痛苦  也不愤怒
I don't feel miserable or angry.
感觉不好  也不坏
I don't feel good or bad.
我感觉无所谓
I feel nothing...
这种感觉不错
which feels great.
你要干什么
What are you doing?
继续生活
Moving on.
回自己家去  我还藏了不少药
In the direction of my house, where I got some more pills.
如果你不遵医嘱坚持要出院的话
If you're discharging yourself against doctor's orders,
你得在那里打勾
you've got to check that box.
我是名医生
I'm a doctor.
所以  技术上讲
So, technically--
打个勾不比说这么多来得简单吗
Wouldn't it be easier if you just checked the box?
你怎么还在这
Why are you still here?
等护士给我拿来
I'm going as soon as the nurse brings me
治疗湿疹的药我就走
something for my eczema.
我觉得这是在画廊时
I figured it was irritated by the paint thinner
倒在我身上的颜料引起的
poured on me in the gallery.
有什么问题吗
Does this mean something?
那不是湿疹
It's not eczema.
你得的也不是癌症
And it's not cancer.
是韦格纳肉芽肿
It's Wegener's granulomatosis.
活检证实  你所认为的湿疹
Biopsy confirmed that what you thought was eczema
其实是皮下血管膨胀
was actually a swelling of the blood vessels in your skin.
也解释了你的胰腺炎
It also explains the pancreatitis
和脑部的团块
and the mass in your brain.
是可以治疗的
And it's treatable.
治疗方案是什么
What's the treatment?
可以单用激素
We could do steroids alone
减缓你大脑中团块的生长
to shrink the growth in your brain,
但是再做一个疗程的放疗效果会更好
but it's much better to add another course of radiation.
放疗
Radiation?
在我的大脑上吗
On my brain?
上次放疗就让我头脑不清醒
But it made me fuzzy last time.
很难去工作
It was harder to work.
现在还没完全恢复
I am still slowed down from it.
这次会更糟
And it'll get worse.
但是死亡会让你失去思考的能力
But, you know, dying can also do a number on your ability to think.
抱歉  我不能接受放疗
I'm sorry. I can't do the radiation.
他们刚才说这是更好的治疗方案
They just said it was a better treatment.
可以救你一命
It could save your life.
倘若不能创作  我的生命又有何意义
My life's not worth anything if I can't do my art.
你还有朋友
You have friends,
关心你的人们
people who care about you.
这是我的大脑  我的工作
This is my brain, my work,
我的人生  卢卡
and my life, Luca.
你拥有的岂止于此
You have more.
这不再是什么伟大的表演作品了
This is not some great performance piece anymore.
只是纯粹的疯狂
This is just crazy.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我无法眼睁睁看着你死去
I can't watch you die...
尤其在明知你可以活下去的情况下
not when you can save yourself.
再见  阿夫松
Good-bye, Afsoun.
你够狠的
Good for you.
-那么  -那么
- So. - So.
我当年为什么要禁止餐厅售酒呢
Why did I ever ban alcohol from the cafeteria?
差点忘了  还有把梳子
Before I forget, there's a brush.
玳瑁柄  鬃毛梳
Tortoise-shell handle, natural bristles--
没在盒子里
wasn't in the box.
如果你能找找的话
If you could look for it...
无故失踪了
Like the Lindbergh baby.
你有在约会吗
You dating anyone?
我们没必要...
We don't have to--
人们吃饭时不都聊这种话题嘛
Look, it's just standard lunch conversation.
我们不适用
Not for us.
好吧  如果你认为
Okay, well, if you've gone over
我们"什么都不能聊"的话
to the "We don't talk about things" side,
我还有其它事等着做呢
then I've got a pot roast in the oven.
没有
No.
分手之后我还没约会过
I haven't dated anyone since you.
人们常说  一朝瘸腿
Well, you know what they say-- once you go gimp...
来谈谈你的腿吧
We s-should talk about your leg.
你觉得我有解不开的心结
You think I have unresolved issues,
而你就是我的心结
and you are the unresolved issues.
没错
Yes.
但是  我觉得还不仅如此
But it's--it's-- I think it's more than that.
还有你的人生  你的选择
It's your life, your choices.
我这么做是为了让人生走上正轨
I did it to fix my life.
不对  等等
No, wait.
不  我这么做是因为我极度抑郁
No, I did it because I'm a deeply unhappy person.
不不  我这么做是为了博取你的同情
No--no, I did it to get sympathy from you.
我这么做是为了惹毛你
I did it to piss you off.
是因为我忘不了你
I did it because I'm not over you.
或者我已经忘了  我要继续生活
Or I was over you, and I was moving on.
我这么做是因为我想知道
I did it because I wanted to know
没有痛苦是什么感觉
what it's like not to be in pain.
我这么做是因为我想更痛苦
I did it because I want to feel more pain.
不管理由是什么
Whatever the reason,
都不成理由  是个错误的决定
it was a bad reason and a bad idea.
这才是关键
That's all that matters.
你好好吃吧
Good lunch.
豪斯
House.
跟我聊聊
Talk to me!
已经说过了
I already did.
不  你只是回放了一遍
No, you just parroted back
过去几天我和威尔森跟你说过的话
what Wilson and I've been saying to you the last few days.
-让开  -不
- Get out of my way. - No.
你把缝线扯开了
Oh, you pulled a stitch.
豪斯  求你和我说说话
House, please just talk to me.
你想知道我现在的感受吗
You want to know how I feel?
我很受伤
I feel hurt.
我知道
I know.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我是不是做错了
Did I make the wrong choice?
五年了
Five years,
每次开幕  每次布置展场
through every opening, every installation,
每一天每一夜
every day and every night,
他一直都在我身边
he was there the whole time.
除了你第一次确诊的时候
Except the first time you were diagnosed.
你和他分了手
You broke up with him,
那你就得独自承担那一切
and you had to go through all of that alone.
也许你创作这个作品的真正原因
Maybe that's the real reason you're doing this piece--
是为了让他陪着你
so that this time you can have him with you.
你还有机会
You still could.
莉莎·卡迪
Lisa Cuddy.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
那天的事非常抱歉
I'm sorry about the other day.
我  最近的生活诸事不顺
I...there were some personal things going on in my life,
那天状态不是很好
and I wasn't at my best.
回想一下
Well, in retrospect,
我的做法也确实有点唐突
my approach could've come off as a little creepy.
没有
No.
如果打个分
On a scale from one to creepy,
至多算是令人紧张吧
you were maybe mildly unnerving.
瑞秋
Rache.
抱歉我没接你电话
Sorry I ducked your calls.
我一直在犯同样的错误  可是有时
I keep making the same mistakes, but at some point
克里斯
Chris,
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
我
I...
真是没想到
didn't expect that.
不好意思
Sorry.
只是看看我小弟弟缝合得怎样
Just checking the stitches on my penis.
你的腿没事吧
Your leg okay?
-在愈合  -那就好
- It's healing. - Good.
我过来取放疗方案表
Just came to grab the radiation-therapy forms.
-什么  -阿夫松改主意了
- What? - Afsoun changed her mind.
出去
Get out.
你已经作出决定了
You made a decision.
-我改变主意了  -为什么
- I changed my mind. - Why?
因为还有更重要的东西...
Because there are more important things than...
比什么重要  你的头脑
Than what... than your brain,
你的能力吗
your abilities?
你的能力是一切的源泉
It's where everything comes from...
生活的意义  幸福  都源自于此
any meaning in your life, any happiness.
不是所有的幸福
Not all happiness...
他抛弃过你一次  还会再次抛弃你
He's already left once. He's gonna leave you again.
你不需要依赖那些只会令你失望的人
You don't need to depend on people who are gonna let you down.
如果你这样做  就是个可悲的伪君子
If you do this, you're a pathetic hypocrite.
等于是说在遇到他之前  你的生活与事业
You're saying that your whole life, all your work up until him
-都毫无意义  -你为什么要这样
- was a pointless... - Why are you doing this?
豪斯  我能听到你的电话在响
House, I can hear your phone ringing.
你没事吧
You alright?
你跟卡迪一起吃的午餐
You had lunch with Cuddy?
对
Yeah.
如何
How was it?
番茄汁意面是冷的
The pasta arrabbiata was cold.
不如我们出去喝一杯
Why don't we get a drink?
去"原木坊"怎么样
We could go to the Sawmill.
顺路去卡迪家
Cuddy's is on the way.
我得把这个还她
I need to return this.
你担心她头发突然打结了不成
You think she's going to have an emergency tangle?
心里总想着
It was on my mind.
早还早了事
I want to get it off.
要我一起去吗
Want me to come?
怕我惹麻烦吗
If I get in trouble?
不过是去送把梳子而已
I'm delivering a hair brush.
刚才发生什么事了
What just happened?
下车
Get out.
发生什么事了
What just happened?
下车
Get out.
豪斯  你为什么生气
House, what are you mad about?
发泄出来  感觉会好些
Just let it out. You'll feel better.
你说得对  我感觉好多了
You're right. I feel much better.
再来一杯吗
You want another one?
不必  我喝够了
No, I think I've had enough.
你说我今天该做些什么呢
What do you think I should do today?
不知道  回家去
I don't know. Go home?
今晚不回
Not tonight.
干杯
Cheers.